Hi everyone, welcome to a new video on the Piece of French channel! Hope
you are doing well. Today is August 31, 2021 and tomorrow we are moving! "Déménager" means
moving to another apartment, changing house, taking all your things, all your furniture,
all your clothes and going to another accommodation, to another apartment. Before
moving, there is the apartment search phase. If you are in France and
want to look for an apartment, you can go to sites like leboncoin or seloger.com
and search there. So you write in which city or neighborhood you are looking for,
what is your budget, how many rooms you want, you can enter all your criteria
and then look at the search results and go visit apartments to choose
which apartment you want. So we had several criteria in our
apartment search. First of all, we wanted at least two (2) rooms. So be careful in the rooms,
we do not count the bathroom, the kitchen or the toilets. We only count the
living rooms, that is to say the living room and the bedrooms. So we were looking for a
minimum 2-room apartment , ideally 3-room apartment, so we wanted a living room and a bedroom and
I wanted an office area so that I could have a place to work quietly since I work
from home. We wanted the apartment not to be too far from Doron's work
so a 30-minute trip maximum by electric bike, to be easy to park,
to park the car, that was also important for us, that there are plenty of parking spots
and a garden or a balcony, that's a plus. So finally we found,
as I told you in my last video, we are actually going to replace our neighbors.
We're going to take over our neighbors' apartment so it's the easiest. They have a 2-room apartment
with a garden so that will be good for us. So once we have looked for the apartment,
found the apartment, it's time to move and we have to pack the boxes!
This is a box. When we move, we need a lot of boxes to put all our
things. So in each box, we put a type of thing to keep it organized so there,
for example, we have books. So there we put the books. Here too, there are other books,
there are the office stuff that Doron is sorting because when you move,
it's also an opportunity to sort and throw away unnecessary things or to give away things that
are not used so it's really an opportunity to sort. So there, we're going to make the boxes,
put the clothes in the boxes, the dishes in the boxes too and to
make it a little more fun, we're going to put on some music because it's
always more fun with a little music and at the moment I really like the French group "Bon
Entendeur" so I advise you to go listen and we will put it on right away.
It's time for coffee break
We made some good progress and now, we are doing a small coffee break,
we made cold coffee because it's super hot today but yeah otherwise it is going well
What that do we have to do? Organize the kitchen, also the whole outside of the house,
all the plants ... We are not finished, it will take a long time!
Hello, it's D-Day, it's moving day. It is almost eight (8) o'clock
and the movers will be arriving soon. The movers are the people who will
come and move the apartment, who will come and take all the furniture and boxes
and bring them to the new apartment. It's a company that does that. In general,
when moving, the movers come with a truck to put all
the furniture but here as it is really close, I think they will come without a truck
and I am sure you are dying to see it the apartment, that you really want to
see the apartment and that you are just waiting for that so I suggest that we go and see
it immediately when it is still empty and there is nothing in it so come on, let's go!
So this is what the apartment looks like. So there,
we are in the kitchen, here is the living room. I turn on the light.
So there is the bathroom with the toilet and the shower.
Then there is a bedroom and above all a large garden, so there we have a garden
Here is the empty apartment. As you can see,
it's a lot bigger than our current apartment so we're really
happy to have some space. There is also plenty of storage, place to store but
yeah we are so happy. Look, I have space, I have space !! Ahhh, so good!
Okay, the movers are coming so I have to go.
We have finally finished the move, all the boxes are here. We started at 9:30 am,
it is 1:00 pm so it took us three and a half hours to move everything. We are exhausted
and we are starving, we are very hungry and since we cannot cook because everything is still
in the boxes, we are going to eat outside and we really want to eat a falafel.
I just woke up from a nap. We were exhausted after the move, we were exhausted,
tired so we inaugurated the new apartment and took a nap. Now, it is 4:45 p.m.
and we will move on to the second stage. So after the move, there is the moving in. "Emmenager"
means moving into a new home so this is the moment when we will unpack the boxes.
After having paked the boxes, we will unpack the boxes so this is really the moment
when we settle in, where we take our marks in a new home, where we take possession
of a new home, we call that moving in. I will finish the vlog here but don't worry,
I will keep you posted in future videos on the progress of the decoration of the apartment and
the layout of the apartment, maybe even we will do a housewarming party when it's all
over. A housewarming party is when you move into a new home,
invite friends over and have a little party to inaugurate the house, it's called a
housewarming party. So we'll see. If you want to follow all of this, I invite you to subscribe
to the channel if you haven't already done so and to activate the notifications so as not to miss the next
videos. Tell me in the comments what vocabulary word you learned in this
video in French, I'm interested and tell me did you move recently,
how did the move go? Tell me in the comments. I kiss you,
take care of you and see you next Wednesday in a new video, bye!